mindsphere.io 2018-06-26

# Siemens | MindSphere | Legal

Privacy Policy

* * *

### Siemens Data Privacy Policy

Status: 02.02.2015

Protecting the security and privacy of your personal data is important to Siemens. Therefore, the Siemens company referred to under "Corporate Information" ("Siemens") operates its websites in compliance with applicable laws on data privacy protection and data security.  
In the following, we provide information on the kinds of data we collect on these Siemens websites, the purposes for which we use such data, and the parties with which we share such data, where applicable.

### Collected data and purpose of processing

We employ cookies on these websites. You will find additional information on this subject in our Cookie Policy. This policy also tells you how to block the use of cookies and the use of data collected by cookies in anonymized or pseudonymized usage profiles.  
Accesses to our website are logged for the purpose of security analysis reports and to defend against cyber-attacks. With the exception of the IP address, no personal data is ever collected or used in this connection. IP addresses are analyzed only in the event of a cyber-attack. Log data is promptly deleted on a regular basis.  
In addition, we collect personal data (e.g., names, addresses, telephone numbers, or e-mail addresses) in connection with the operation of our websites only when you have voluntarily provided such data to us (e.g., through registration, contact inquiries, surveys, etc.) and when we are entitled to process or use such data by virtue of permission granted by you or on the basis of a statutory provision.  
As a general rule, we use such data only for the purpose for which you divulged the data to us, such as to answer your inquiries, process your orders, or grant you access to certain information or offerings.

### Sharing of data

Insofar as you have provided your consent or when we are otherwise legally entitled to do so, we will share your personal data with subsidiaries of Siemens, where applicable, for the purposes indicated above.  
In connection with the operation of its website and the services provided by way of the website, Siemens works with service providers such as hosting or IT maintenance service providers, for example.  
These recipients may possibly be located in countries outside of the European Economic Area ("third countries"), in which applicable laws do not offer the same level of data privacy protection as in your home country. In such cases, Siemens takes measures to ensure an appropriate level of data privacy protection. For example, we share your personal data with Siemens subsidiaries in third countries only if they have implemented our Binding Corporate Rules ("BCR") for the protection of personal data. You will find additional information on the Siemens BCR under "Downloads."  
Data is shared only in connection with and in compliance with applicable laws and regulations. We do not sell or otherwise market your personal data to third parties.

### Questions and comments; changes

Siemens will respond to all legitimate requests for information and where applicable, to correct, amend, or delete your personal data. If you wish to make such a request or if you have questions or comments about this Data Privacy Policy, please click on "[Contact](http://www.siemens.com/contact/en/corporate/general.php)" to send us your questions and suggestions.  
This Data Privacy Policy is updated from time to time. You will find the date of the last update at the top of this page.

### Siemens Cookie Policy

**This Cookie Policy applies to the present website operated by the Siemens company referred to under "Corporate Information."**

Status: August 2016

When you visit Siemens websites, information is stored on your terminal device in the form of a "cookie." Cookies are small files that are stored on your terminal device and save certain settings and data to exchange with our websites via your browser.  
For example, cookies enable us to tailor a website to better match your interests or to store your password so that you do not have to re-enter it every time. As a general rule, we never collect personal data via cookies, unless you have given us your express permission to do so.  
If you do not want us to recognize your terminal device, please configure your Internet browser to erase all cookies from your device, to block all cookies or to receive a warning before a cookie is stored. You will find brief instructions on how to do this below.  
Please note that certain functions of our website may no longer work, or not correctly, without cookies.

### Types of cookies

Cookies can be assigned to four categories, depending on their function and intended purpose: absolutely necessary cookies, performance cookies, functional cookies, and cookies for marketing purposes.

**Absolutely necessary cookies**  
are needed for you to navigate within Siemens websites and operate basic website functions, such as the issuance of anonymous Session IDs for bundling several related queries to a server.

**Performance cookies**  
collect information on the usage of our websites, including for example the Internet browsers and operating systems used, the domain name of the website which you previously visited, the number of visits, average duration of visit, and pages called up.  
These cookies do not store any information that would make it possible to personally identify the user. The information collected with the aid of these cookies is aggregated and is therefore anonymous. Performance cookies serve the purpose of improving the user friendliness of a website and therefore enhancing the user’s experience. You can block the use of such cookies by creating an exclusion cookie (see "managing cookies" below).

**Functional cookies**  
enable a website to store information the user has already entered (such as user ID, language selection, or the user’s location), in order to offer improved, personalized functions to the user. Functional cookies are also used to enable requested functions such as playing videos and to make a user’s decision to block or disable a certain function (e.g. web analysis) persistent ("opt-out cookies").

**Cookies for marketing purposes**  
are used to offer more relevant content to users, based on their specific interests. They are also used to limit the display frequency of an ad and to measure and control the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. They register whether users have visited a website or not, and which contents were used. This information may possibly also be shared with third parties, such as advertisers, for example. These cookies are often linked to the functions of third-party websites. You can block the use of such cookies by creating an opt-out cookie (see "managing cookies" below).

### Managing cookies:

**Please note: Not all of the cookies mentioned below will necessarily be used when you browse our website using a mobile terminal device**

**Performance cookies: Adobe Analytics**  
We use Adobe Analytics on our website for the purpose of constantly improving the website and/or detecting errors. For this purpose, Adobe Analytics anonymously stores and analyzes various kinds of data, including the visited website and the website’s metadata, websites that link to Siemens, the time of the visit, and the browser used.  
Please click [here](http://www.d1.sc.omtrdc.net/optout.html?locale=en_US&second=1&second_has_cookie=0) to prevent Adobe Analytics from aggregating and analyzing the data collected from your visit to this website. By doing this, you will create a so-called exclusion cookie in your browser. It contains no personal data, but technically enables Adobe Analytics to permanently recognize your preference.  
If you delete this exclusion cookie or if you change your computer or web browser, you will need to create the exclusion cookie again.Cookies for marketing purposes.

**Cookies for marketing purposes  
Adobe Target**  
We use Adobe Target to provide content that is specifically tailored to the interests of users. For this purpose, Adobe Target analyzes anonymized information about your previous visits to our website.  
Please click [here](http://siemens.tt.omtrdc.net/optout) to prevent Adobe Target from aggregating and analyzing the data collected from your visit of this website. By doing this, you will create a so-called exclusion cookie in your browser. It contains no personal data, but technically enables Adobe/Siemens to permanently recognize your Preference.Preference.

**Adobe Media Optimizer**  
We sometimes run online advertisement campaigns that display advertisements ("ads") to you based on your likely interests. We may learn your likely interests based on your use of our websites and applications, or from other companies and websites that we work with to help us understand your likely interests. These types of ads are often called "online behavioral advertising." We use Adobe Media Optimizer ("AMO") to display our ads on websites across the Internet. For this purpose several cookies will be set in your browser allowing both AMO and so-called ad exchanges to recognize your terminal device based on anonymous identifiers and to thus show you ads tailored to your likely interests. Please click [here](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out.html) to prevent AMO from aggregating and analyzing the data collected from your visit of this website (web viewing data) and serving you tailored ads shown on other websites based on your activity on our websites and online services. If you opt out, you may still see our ads on other companies’ websites, but they will not be specifically tailored to you based on your activity on our websites and online services. In addition you may also opt out from the collection of web viewing data for interest-based advertising by some or all of the companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance on the [Digital Advertising Alliance Consumer Choice page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

**Xaxis**  
We permit the company Xaxis (a division of GroupM Competence Center GmbH, Derendorfer Allee 10, 40476 Düsseldorf), to place cookies on our websites that collect information on usage-based online advertising; this is also known as "targeting."  
For this purpose, Xaxis collects and stores anonymized data on our website. The cookie stored on your computer collects information about your activities on the websites you have visited (e.g., surfing behavior, sub-pages visited, ad banners clicked, etc.). Based on this data, Xaxis generates profiles that do cannot be used for personal identification, meaning that you as the user cannot be personally identified; in particular, the IP address you use is not stored.  
Your computer is then identified for ad delivery purposes and assigned to a target group. This information makes it possible to display advertising that is more relevant to you on the websites of other providers.  
You will find additional information on the technology used on our website and on data privacy at the following link: <http://www.xaxis.com/page/privacy-policy>  
You can always block the future collection and storage of data by creating an [exclusion cookie](http://www.xaxis.com/common/OPT-OUT_call.html).

### How can I deactivate cookies?

In the following you will find a summary of links that provide detailed information on the deactivation of cookies in commonly used browsers.  
**If you have any further questions about our Cookie Policy, please click on "[Contact](http://www.siemens.com/contact/en/corporate/general.php)" to send us your questions and suggestions.**  
This Cookie Policy is updated from time to time. You will find the date of the latest update at the top of this page.

### **1\. Scope**

1.1. Any use of this web site provided by Siemens Aktiengesellschaft and/or its affiliates ("Siemens"), "Siemens Web Site", is subject to these Terms of Use. These Terms of Use may be amended, modified or replaced by other terms and conditions, e.g . for the purchase of products and services. With log-in, or where a log-in is not required, in accessing or using the Siemens Web Site these Terms of Use are accepted in their then current version.  
1.2. In the case of Web offers aimed at companies or public enterprises, such companies or enterprises are represented by the user and must assume that the user has appropriate knowledge and acts accordingly.  
1.3. If the User uses this Siemens Web Site as business customer, i.e. that it is not acting for purposes which are outside its trade, business or profession, or as administration customer, § 312i para. 1 sentence 1 no. 1 - 3 of the German Civil Code does not apply.

### **2\. Services**

2.1. This Siemens Web Site contains specific information and software, as well as - as the case may be - related documentation, for viewing or downloading.  
2.2. Siemens may stop the operation of the Siemens Web Site in full or in part at any time. Due to the nature of the internet and computer systems, Siemens cannot accept any liability for the continuous availability of the Siemens Web Site.

### **3\. Registration, Password**

3.1. Some pages of the Siemens Web Site may be password protected. In the interest of safety and security of the business transactions, only registered Users may access said pages. Siemens reserves the right to deny registration to any User. Siemens particularly reserves the right to determine certain sites, which were previously freely accessible, subject to registration. Siemens is entitled, at any time and without obligation to give reasons, to deny the User the right to access the password-protected area by blocking its User Data (as defined below), in particular if the User  
\- uses false data for the purpose of registration;  
\- violates these Terms of Use or neglects its duty of care with regard to User Data;  
\- violates any applicable laws in the access to or use of the Siemens Web Site; or  
\- did not use the Siemens Web Site for a longer period.  
3.2. For registration the User shall give accurate information and, where such information changes over time, update such information (to the extent possible: online) without undue delay. The User shall ensure that its e-mail address, as supplied to Siemens, is current at all times and an address at which the User can be contacted.  
3.3. Upon registration the User will be provided with an access code, comprising a User ID and a password ("User Data"). On first access the User shall promptly change the password received from Siemens into a password known only to the User. The User Data allows the User to view or change its data or, as applicable, to withdraw its consent to data processing.  
3.4. The User shall ensure that User Data is not accessible by third parties and is liable for all transactions and other activities carried out under its User Data. At the end of each online session, the User shall log-off from the password protected websites. If and to the extent the User becomes aware that third parties are misusing its User Data the User shall notify Siemens thereof without undue delay in writing, or, as the case may be, by e-mail.  
3.5. After receipt of the notice under paragraph 3.4, Siemens will deny access to the password-protected area under such User Data. Access by the User will only be possible again upon the User's application to Siemens or upon new registration.  
3.6. The User may at any time request termination of its registration in writing, provided that the deletion will not violate the proper performance of contractual relationships. In such event Siemens will remove all user data and other stored personally identifiable data of the User as soon as these data are no longer needed.

### **4\. Rights of Use to Information, Software and Documentation**

4.1. The use of any information, software and documentation made available on or via this Siemens Web Site is subject to these Terms of Use or, in case of updating information, software or documentation, subject to the applicable license terms previously agreed to with Siemens. Separately agreed to license terms, for example software downloads, shall prevail over these Terms of Use.  
4.2. Siemens grants User a non-exclusive and non-transferable license, which may not be sublicensed, to use the information, software and documentation made available to the User on or via the Siemens Web Site to the extent agreed, or in the event of no such agreement to the extent of the purpose intended by Siemens in making same available.  
4.3. Software shall be made available at no expense in object code. There shall be no right for the source code to be made available. This shall not apply to source code related to open source software, which license conditions take priority over these Terms of Use in the case of transfer of open source software and which conditions require the making available of the source code. In such case Siemens shall make the source code available in return for the payment of costs.  
4.4. Information, software and documentation may not be distributed by the User to any third party at any time nor may it be rented or in any other way made available. Unless such is allowed by mandatory law, the User shall not modify the software or documentation nor shall it disassemble, reverse engineer or decompile the software or separate any part thereof. The User may make one backup copy of the software where necessary to secure further use in accordance with these Terms of Use.  
4.5. The information, software and documentation are protected by copyright laws as well as international copyright treaties as well as other laws and conventions related to intellectual property. The User shall observe such laws and in particular shall not modify, conceal or remove any alphanumeric code, marks or copyright notices neither from the information nor from the software or documentation, or any copies thereof.  
4.6. §§ 69a et seq. of the German Copyright Law shall not be affected hereby.

### **5\. Intellectual Property**

5.1. Notwithstanding the particular provisions in § 4 of these Terms of Use, information, brand names and other contents of the Siemens Web Site may not be changed, copied, reproduced, sold, rented, used, supplemented or otherwise used in any other way without the prior written permission of Siemens.  
5.2. Except for the rights of use and other rights expressly granted herein, no other rights are granted to the User nor shall any obligation be implied requiring the grant of further rights. Any and all patent rights and licenses are expressly excluded.  
5.3. Siemens may, without charge, use any ideas or proposals stored by a User on the Siemens Web Sites for the development, improvement and sale of its products.

### **6\. Duties of the User**

6.1. In accessing or using the Siemens Web Site the User shall not  
\- harm other persons, in particular minors, or infringe their personal rights;  
\- breach public morality in its manner of use;  
\- violate any intellectual property right or any other proprietary right;  
\- upload any contents containing a virus, so-called Trojan Horse, or any other program that could damage data;  
\- transmit, store or upload hyperlinks or contents to which the User is not entitled, in particular in cases where such hyperlinks or contents are in breach of confidentiality obligations or unlawful; or  
\- distribute advertising or unsolicited e-mails (so-called "spam") or inaccurate warnings of viruses, defects or similar material and the User shall not solicit or request the participation in any lottery, snowball system, chain letter, pyramid game or similar activity.  
6.2. Siemens may deny access to the Siemens Web Site at any time, in particular if the User breaches any obligation arising from these Terms of Use.

### **7\. Hyperlinks**

The Siemens Web Site may contain hyperlinks to the web pages of third parties. Siemens shall have no liability for the contents of such web pages and does not make representations about or endorse such web pages or their contents as its own, as Siemens does not control the information on such web pages and is not responsible for the contents and information given thereon. The use of such web pages shall be at the sole risk of the User.

### **8\. Liability for defects of title or quality**

8.1. Insofar as any information, software or documentation is made available at no cost, any liability for defects as to quality or title of the information, software and documentation especially in relation to the correctness or absence of defects or the absence of claims or third party rights or in relation to completeness and/or fitness for purpose are excluded except for cases involving willful misconduct or fraud.  
8.2. The information on the Siemens Web Site may contain specifications or general descriptions related to the technical possibilities of individual products which may not be available in certain cases (e.g. due to product changes). The required performance of the product shall therefore be mutually agreed in each case at the time of purchase.

### **9\. Other Liability, Viruses**

9.1. The liability of Siemens for defects in relation to quality and title shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of § 8 of these Terms of Use. Any further liability of Siemens is excluded unless required by law, e.g. under the Act on Product Liability or in cases of willful misconduct, gross negligence, personal injury or death, failure to meet guaranteed characteristics, fraudulent concealment of a defect or in case of breach of fundamental contractual obligations. The damages in case of breach of fundamental contractual obligations is limited to the contract-typical, foreseeable damage if there is no willful misconduct or gross negligence.  
9.2. Although Siemens makes every endeavor to keep the Siemens Web Site free from viruses, Siemens cannot make any guarantee that it is virus-free. The User shall, for its own protection, take the necessary steps to ensure appropriate security measures and shall utilize a virus scanner before downloading any information, software or documentation.  
9.3. §§ 9.1 and 9.2 do not intend nor imply any changes to the burden of proof to the User's disadvantage.

### **10\. Compliance with Export Control Regulations**

10.1. If the User transfers information, software and documentation provided by Siemens to a third party, the User shall comply with all applicable national and international (re-) export control regulations. In any event of such transfer the User shall comply with the (re-) export control regulations of the Federal Republic of Germany, of the European Union and of the United States of America.  
10.2. Prior to any such transfer to a third party the User shall in particular check and guarantee by appropriate measures that  
\- There will be no infringement of an embargo imposed by the European Union, by the United States of America and/ or by the United Nations by such transfer or by provision of other economic resources in connection with information, software and documentation provided by Siemens, also considering the limitations of domestic business and prohibitions of by-passing those embargos;  
\- Such information, software and documentation provided by Siemens are not intended for use in connection with armaments, nuclear technology or weapons, if and to the extent such use is subject to prohibition or authorization, unless required authorization is provided;  
\- The regulations of all applicable Sanctioned Party Lists of the European Union and the United States of America concerning the trading with entities, persons and organizations listed therein are considered.  
10.3. If required to enable authorities or Siemens to conduct export control checks, the User, upon request by Siemens, shall promptly provide Siemens with all information pertaining to the particular end-user, the particular destination and the particular intended use of information, software and documentation provided by Siemens, as well as any export control restrictions existing.  
10.4. The User shall indemnify and hold harmless Siemens from and against any claim, proceeding, action, fine, loss, cost and damages arising out of or relating to any noncompliance with export control regulations by the User, and the User shall compensate Siemens for all losses and expenses resulting thereof, unless such noncompliance was not caused by fault of the User. This provision does not imply a change in burden of proof.  
10.5. Siemens' obligation to fulfill an agreement is subject to the proviso that the fulfillment is not prevented by any impediments arising out of national and international foreign trade and customs requirements or any embargos or other sanctions.

### **11\. Data Privacy Protection**

For collection, use and processing of personally identifiable data of the User of the Siemens Web Site, Siemens shall comply with applicable laws on data privacy protection and the Siemens Web Site Data Protection Privacy Policy, which is available per hyperlink on the Siemens Web Site and/or on www.siemens.com.

### **12\. Supplementary Agreements, Place of Jurisdiction, Applicable Law**

12.1. Any supplementary agreement requires the written form.  
12.2. The place of jurisdiction shall be Munich if the User is a merchant in terms of the German Commercial Code (Handelsgesetzbuch).  
12.3. The individual pages of the Siemens Web Site are operated and administered by Siemens Aktiengesellschaft and/or its affiliates. The pages comply with the law applicable in the country where the responsible company has its business residence. Siemens makes no representation that information, software and/or documentation on the Siemens Web Site are appropriate or available for viewing or downloading at locations outside such country. If Users access Siemens Web Site from outside such country, they are exclusively responsible for compliance with all applicable local laws. Access to Siemens Web Site's information, software and/or documentation from countries where such content is unlawful is prohibited. In this case and where User seeks to do business with Siemens, the User should contact the Siemens representative for the particular country for country specific business.  
12.4. These Terms of Use shall be governed by - and all disputes relating to or in connection with these Terms of Use or their subject matter shall be resolved in accordance with - the laws of Germany, to the exclusion of its conflict of laws rules. The application of the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sales of Goods (CISG) of 11 April 1980 is excluded.
